CONTACT Information 5807 S. Woodlawn Avenue E-mail: yzhong0@chicagobooth.edu

Chicago, IL 60637 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yueyang-zhong

Tel: (+1)773-595-8582 Personal Website: https://yzhong0.github.io/yueyangzhong/

RESEARCH INTERESTS My primary research interests are stochastic modeling of service systems with consideration of human strategic behavior and unknown systemic information. My research uses tools from applied probability, game theory, and learning theory (in particular, online learning and reinforcement learning).

I am currently working on (i) system design optimization problems in queueing systems with strategic customers and strategic servers; and (ii) online learning problems in queueing systems in the face of unknown system parameters, such as learning to schedule in multiclass many-server queues.

EDUCATION

#### The University of Chicago Booth School of Business

Chicago, IL

• Ph.D. in Operations Management (Minor in Applied Probability) 2018–2023 (expected)

• Master of Business Administration 2021–2023 (expected)

• Advisor: Professor Amy R. Ward

# Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

• B.S. in Industrial Engineering (Minor in Economics) with Honors

2014-2018

2016

Publications & Papers Under Review

- [1] Yueyang Zhong, John R. Birge, Amy R. Ward. 2022. Learning the Scheduling Policy in Time-Varying Multiclass Many Server Queues. *Major Revision at Operations Research*. [Link]
- [2] Yueyang Zhong, Ragavendran Gopalakrishnan, Amy R. Ward. 2021. Behavior-Aware Queueing: The Finite-Buffer Setting with Strategic Servers. *Minor Revision at Operations Research*. [Link]
- [3] Yueyang Zhong, Zhixi Wan, Zuo-Jun Max Shen. 2020. Queueing Versus Surge Pricing Mechanism: Efficiency, Equity, and Consumer Welfare. Reject and Resubmit at Management Science. [Link]
- [4] Yueyang Zhong, Amy R. Ward, Amber L. Puha. 2022. Asymptotically Optimal Idling in the GI/GI/N+GI Queue. Operations Research Letters. [Link]
- [5] Yueyang Zhong, YeeMan Bergstrom, Amy R. Ward. 2020. Data-Driven Market-Making via Model-Free Learning. In Proceedings of the Twenty-Ninth International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI-20): Special Track on AI in FinTech. [Link]

WORK IN PROGRESS

- [a] **Yueyang Zhong**, Ragavendran Gopalakrishnan, Amy R. Ward. Some Properties of the Erlang B and C Formulae. *Working paper (Available upon request)*.
- [b] Yueyang Zhong, Ragavendran Gopalakrishnan, Amy R. Ward. Price of Anarchy in Behavior-Aware Queues with Strategic Arrivals and Strategic Servers. Work in progress.
- [c] Yueyang Zhong, Ragavendran Gopalakrishnan, Amy R. Ward. An Experimental Investigation of Strategic Server Behavior in Queueing Contexts. Work in progress.
- [d] Yueyang Zhong, John R. Birge, Amy R. Ward. Learning to Schedule in Multiclass Many Server Queues with Abandonment: An Instance-Independent Regret. Work in progress.
- [e] **Yueyang Zhong**. Online Advertising Strategy for Long-Term Good via Robust IV-Q-learning with Noisy Instruments. *Working paper (Available upon request)*.

Honors and Awards

- Finalist, INFORMS Conference On Service Science, Best Service Science Student Paper 2021
- Booth School of Business Ph.D. Fellowship 2018–2023
- Distinguished Undergraduate Thesis Award, Tsinghua University 2018
- Outstanding Undergraduate Award, Tsinghua University 2018
- Tung OOCL Scholarship, Weiming Zhang Scholarship 2015–2017
- Student Overseas Research Grant 2017
- First Prize, Chinese Physics Olympiad

#### Presentations

• CSAMSE, Virtual [1]	July 2022
• INFORMS CORS, Vancouver, BC [2],[1]	June~2022
• POMS, Virtual [2]	$April\ 2022$
• NYU MOILS Seminar, Virtual [1]	Feb 2022
• INFORMS Annual Meeting, Anaheim, CA [1]	Oct 2021
• MSOM Conference Meeting, Virtual [2]	June 2021
• POMS, Virtual [5]	May 2021
• UCSD Stochastic Systems Seminar, Virtual [2],[4]	April 2021
• IJCAI-PRICAI, Virtual [5]	Jan 2021
• INFORMS Conference on Service Science, Virtual [3]	Dec 2020
• INFORMS Annual Meeting, Virtual [2]	Nov 2020
• MD4SG, Virtual [3]	Aug 2020
• INFORMS Annual Meeting, Seattle, WA [3]	Oct 2019
• INFORMS Annual Meeting, Phoenix, AZ [3]	Nov 2018

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# The University of Chicago Booth School of Business

Teaching Assistant (MBA Program)

BUSN 41100: Applied Regression Analysis (MBA core)

Fall 2020, Fall 2021

- This course covers topics on regression and its implementation in R (Enrollment: 200+).
- Assisted students with R in weekly office hours, and held weekly R sessions.

BUSN 40000: Operations Management: Business Process Fundamentals (MBA core) Winter 2020

- This course covers operations concepts through cases integrated with theory (Enrollment: 200+).
- Independently held two review sessions, and prepared midterm and final exam questions.

BUSN 40110: Managing Service Operations (MBA elective)

Winter 2022

- This course draws on ideas from the core MBA course BUSN 40000, and focuses on the basics to analyze and design services ones in which customers are involved (Enrollment: 80+).
- Assisted students with homework questions in weekly office hours, and supervised student groups developing case materials in collaboration with multiple companies for the final project.
- Independently held a final review session.

## Industry Experience

### Pinterest Labs

Remote

Research Intern, Ads Marketplace team

June 2021-Sept 2021

• Designed and implemented a causal reinforcement learning algorithm to dynamically control the ad load leading to over 30% improvement in the yearly ad revenue from offline evaluation.

#### Blue Fire Capital, LLC

Chicago, IL

Research Intern, Data Science Group

July 2019-Sept 2019

• Developed a reinforcement learning based trading strategy, which passed the firm's backtest with a Sharpe ratio above 3 and tripled the cumulative PnL over one month; see [5] for reference.

DiDi

Beijing, China

Research Intern, Research Center of Innovation and Operations

Jan 2018-July 2018

• Built a theoretical queueing model to explain the firm's strategy transition from the surge pricing mechanism to the virtual queueing mechanism, which improves the passenger request fulfillment rate by 30.6% based on a large-scale data with 10M+ users; see [3] for reference.

SERVICE

Ad-hoc Reviewer: Operations Research, Mathematics of Operations Research, Operations Research

Letters, Service Science, ICSS

Conference organization: Session chair—INFORMS Annual Meeting 2021, INFORMS CORS 2022. Mentoring: Awaid Yasin (Master student, the University of Chicago Division of Social Sciences). Others: Tutor students in the MBA program at Chicago Booth on operations management and

statistics courses.

SELECTED

Linear Programming, Convex Optimization, Infinite Dimensional Optimization, Dynamic Program-PhD Courses ming, Approximate Dynamic Programming, Stochastic Optimization, Online Optimization, Real Analysis, Measure-Theoretic Probability I, III, Stochastic Processes, Brownian Motion and Stochastic Calculus, Queueing Theory, Dynamic Control of Stochastic Networks, Stochastic Calculus and Queueing Applications, Queueing Models for Service Operations Management, Networks: Introduction to Modeling and Analysis, Machine Learning, Statistical Inference, Foundations of Advanced Quantitative Marketing, Microeconomics I, II, Macroeconomics.

SKILLS AND OTHERS

Language: Chinese (native), English (fluent)

Data/Statistical Tools: R, SQL

Optimization Tools: CPLEX, GUROBI, AMPL **Programming Language**: Python, C/C++, JAVA

Hobbies: Piano, Yoga, Sketch, Calligraphy, Traveling, Photography

References

Professor Amy R. Ward

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business 5807 S Woodlawn Ave Chicago, IL 60637

E-mail: amy.ward@chicagobooth.edu

Professor John R. Birge

The University of Chicago Booth School of Business 5807 S Woodlawn Ave Chicago, IL 60637

E-mail: John.Birge@chicagobooth.edu

Professor Raga Gopalakrishnan

Queen's University

Stephen J.R. Smith School of Business

143 Union Street West

Kingston, ON K7L 3N6, Canada E-mail: r.gopalakrishnan@queensu.ca